Previously on the show.
上集說到
Cloud Giant finally returned to the cloud sea tunnel.
雲巨人終於回到了雲海隧道
The giant, Slowy, Mechanical Bird and Wolffy
他和慢羊羊、機械鳥還有灰太狼
told the tale of what happened.
還原出了當年事件的始末
Once the truth has been told,
就在一切真相大白以後
the Cloud Giant begins to put the sky crystal back together.
雲巨人準備要重組天晶了
Will things really go smoothly?
事情真的會這麼順利嗎？
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Final Sky Crystal"
《奇幻天空島之 最後的天晶》
Let's begin then.
那我們開始吧
Sky crystal fragment extraction!
天晶碎片抽取大法！
Extract!
抽！
We're still missing one fragment.
天晶，還缺一塊
Why would we still miss one?
怎麼還會缺一塊呢？
Forget it.
不用想了
Based on my experience, when you lose something,
根據我的經驗，東西不見了
you never find it when you look for it.
你想找它出來，怎麼也找不到
When you stop looking for it, it'll appear on its own.
你不想找的時候，它就會自己出來了
So quit thinking about it.
所以大家還是別想那麼多了
Go back to your normal routine.
該吃就吃，該睡就睡吧
That can't be true, Paddi. Get up and help us look for it.
懶羊羊，怎麼可能嘛！快點起來找
What is that?
什麼東西啊？
Is Paddi right after all?
難道，真的被懶羊羊說中了？
No, this is just a marble.
不，這只是顆彈珠
Weslie, that marble is mine.
喜羊羊哥哥，那彈珠是我的
Willie? Why are you here?
小灰灰，你怎麼會來這裡？
Dad is too busy to play with me.
爸爸太忙了，沒時間陪我玩
He told me to come play with you guys.
他讓我來找你們玩
I'm sorry, Willie. We're too busy to play as well.
對不起啊，小灰灰 我們現在也沒空陪你玩啊
What are you busy with?
那你們現在在忙什麼？
We can't find the last missing sky crystal fragment.
我們正苦惱的呢 最後一塊天晶還沒有找到
I see. Can I borrow your remote control car then?
原來是這樣 那我能借你的遙控汽車玩嗎？
Of course. Go get it from our Magic Train.
當然可以了 你到我們的嘻哈號裡面去拿吧
Thank you, Sparky.
謝謝沸羊羊哥哥
It's about time for Willie to get home.
小灰灰也差不多該回來了
I'm home, Dad!
爸爸，我回來了！
Are you tired, son?
兒子，你累了嗎？
Yes! I'm a bit hungry too.
嗯，肚子也有點餓
Your mom bought tasty snacks. Go and have some.
你媽媽買了好吃的點心 你快點過去吃吧
Okay!
嗯！
Willie, we're too busy to play as well.
小灰灰，我們現在也沒空陪你玩啊
We can't find the last missing sky crystal fragment.
我們正苦惱著 最後一塊天晶到現在還沒有找到
They're missing a sky crystal fragment? Where could it be?
天晶還差一塊，能在哪呢？
Dad!
爸爸
Son, why are you back?
兒子，你怎麼又回來了？
Have you seen the sensor joystick for the remote control car?
你有看到遙控車的感應手柄嗎？
Just a moment. Here!
稍等一下，給你！
Thanks, Dad!
-謝謝爸爸 -不用謝
Sensor joystick...
感應手柄
I know!
我想到了！
Where could the last sky crystal fragment be?
最後一塊天晶會在哪裡呢？
Come to think of it, Wolffy was there the day sky crystal shattered.
現在想想，那天天晶破碎 灰太狼也在現場
Yes, he must have the last fragment!
對，最後一塊天晶 肯定在灰太狼的身上
That's slander! Pure slander! Blatant slander!
你們這是污衊，污衊！ 赤裸裸的污衊！
Wolffy? What do you want?
灰太狼，你想要幹麼？
You keep making false accusations about me!
你們一直冤枉我
You said I stole the colored pencil when you lost it.
顏色筆不見了，就冤枉是我偷的
Then you blamed me for stealing the star diamond.
星星鑽石不見了，也冤枉是我拿的
I'm a simple wolf.
我是一隻很單純的狼
All I want is to eat goats.
只是想吃吃羊而已
Why do you keep falsely accusing me?
你們為什麼一直要冤枉我呢？
We searched him. There are no fragments.
全搜過了，真的沒有碎片
He doesn't have a mark on his hand either.
手上也沒有發現印記
Seems like Wolffy really doesn't have the sky crystal.
看來天晶真的不在灰太狼身上啊
Huh, do you believe I'm innocent now?
現在相信本大王是清白的了吧？
Right, Wolffy, why are you here?
對了，灰太狼，你來幹麼？
It's a long story.
說來話長了
The thing is,
事情是這樣的
the precious gemstone I bought Wolnie, the desert tear, has gone missing.
我給紅紅買了價值連城的寶石 “沙漠之淚”不見了
It might be mixed with Willie's marbles.
可能是混在小灰灰的彈珠裡了
So I'm wondering if it could be with you.
所以我在想會不會在你們這裡呢？
Could Willie have left it on Magic Train when he was playing there?
難道是小灰灰剛才玩的時候 落在嘻哈號裡了？
Can I go look for the gem inside Magic Train?
那你們能讓我進嘻哈號 找一下寶石嗎？
Why don't we let Wolffy in for a look?
要不，我們就讓灰太狼進去看看吧
No! He must be plotting something.
不行，他肯定居心不良
It's fine. The other sky crystal fragments are with Cloud Giant.
沒事，天晶都在雲巨人手上
Magic Train isn't functioning right now.
嘻哈號已經沒有功能了
Go on then, since Village Chief agreed.
去吧，既然村長都同意了
Thank you so much.
太感謝你們了
Hold on!
等一下！
Don't eat my biscuits!
別偷吃我的餅乾
Of course...
當然...
Cloud Giant wants to see us?
雲巨人找我們？
He may have come up with clues on sky crystal. Let's go then.
可能是雲巨人想到了關於天晶的線索 快過去吧
I'm worried about Wolffy's intentions.
我不放心灰太狼啊
Why don't you keep an eye on Wolffy, Paddi?
要不，懶羊羊，你負責盯著灰太狼吧
Yes, since you're so worried that he would eat your biscuits.
對啊，你那麼怕他偷吃你的餅乾
Why me?
為什麼是我？
It's fine. We'll be back soon.
沒事，我們很快就回來了
I'm starving.
好餓啊
Older brother, the chips we got at the mall were so good.
哥哥，剛剛在商場買的薯片很好吃
Remember to buy more next time.
下次記得多買一點
All right.
好的
Snacks? I know what to do!
零食，我想到辦法了
If I guessed right, it must be inside Magic Train.
如果沒有猜錯 東西一定就在嘻哈號裡邊
Wolffy! I'm watching you! Don't try anything funny!
灰太狼，我盯著你呢，別想耍陰謀
Wolffy, I'm watching you!
灰太狼，我盯著你呢，別想耍陰謀！
Since when did Paddi get so serious?
懶羊羊，什麼時候變得這麼認真了？
This isn't like him.
這不符合他的設定啊
Wolffy, I'm watching you!
灰太狼，我盯著你呢
So delicious!
&lrm;好吃…
I am sorry if you feel like I'm showing off.
閃到大家真是不好意思啊
It's all my Wolffy's fault. He insisted on buying me this huge, expensive gem.
都怪我們家灰太狼 非要給我買這麼大這麼貴的寶石
He said it's called desert tear.
還說叫什麼沙漠之淚
Desert tear? Didn't Wolffy say it was lost? Was he...
沙漠之淚？灰太狼不是說不見了嗎？ 難道…
I have some clues.
我想到了一些線索
Could you tell me how you found your missing friends?
想問一下你們之前 是如何尋找失散的伙伴的？
The radar on Magic Train can detect them.
嘻哈號上的雷達可以感應到他們
Based on what I know, only sky crystals can resonate with and detect each other.
據我所知 只有天晶與天晶之間才能相互感應
Oh?
啊？
No wonder the radar started detecting the locations of my other friends
難怪在塔塔鎮 第一次用天晶的能力之後
after using sky crystal for the first time in Tower Town.
雷達就能夠偵測到其他夥伴的位置
So the last sky crystal fragment may very well be in Magic Train.
這麼說來，最後一塊天晶 很有可能就在嘻哈號裡面
Oh, no!
不好了…
Paddi, weren't you supposed to be watching Wolffy?
懶羊羊，不是讓你盯著灰太狼的嗎？
I saw with my own eyes that the gem is still with Wolnie!
我親眼看到，寶石還在紅太狼身上
What?
啊？
So Wolffy went on Magic Train to find the missing sky crystal fragment.
所以灰太狼進嘻哈號 就是為了找出剩下的天晶
Where is it? Why can't I find it?
到底在哪呢？怎麼會找不到呢？
Wolffy, you really are up to no good!
灰太狼，你果然有陰謀
How did they find out so quickly?
居然這麼快就被發現了
Wolffy, we have you surrounded. Hand over the energy extractor now.
灰太狼，你已經被包圍了 快把能量提取器交出來
Come get it, if you dare!
那有本事你們就來搶啊
A camera?
攝像機？
How despicable of you, Wolffy!
灰太狼，你真卑鄙
How could you tap Magic Train to spy on us?
居然在嘻哈號上裝攝像機監視我們
Will you stop making false accusations about me?
你們別一次又一次地 冤枉我好不好啊？
As a high-end inventor, if I were to spy on you,
作為高端發明家，要監視你們的話
would I use such cheap and outdated equipment?
會用這麼沒有技術含量的設備嗎？
If I were to spy on you, I would be using this!
我真要想這樣做 就用這個來監視你們了
Oh! Isn't that Willie's cap?
這不就是小灰灰的帽子嗎？
I can't believe you used Willie to spy on us.
沒想到你為了偷拍我們 居然連小灰灰都利用
You're terrible!
太卑鄙了！
But if this isn't Wolffy's,
可如果這台攝像機不是灰太狼的
who is spying on us then?
那到底是誰在監視我們呢？
Don't think of running, Wolffy!
灰太狼，別想跑
Sky crystal...
天晶…
I'm right, after all. Sky crystal is on Magic Train!
本大王果然沒有猜錯 天晶就在嘻哈號內
Wolffy, you won't get away this time! Hand over sky crystal now!
灰太狼，你今天逃不掉的 還是交出天晶吧
Since I decided to come, I came prepared.
本大王既然敢來 又怎麼會沒有準備呢？
Be careful, everyone!
大家小心啊
Goodbye, goats!
再見了，小羊們
Stop escaping!
別跑！
Hand over sky crystal now!
快交出天晶！
Escape? You are always the ones escaping from me!
逃？一直以來 好像你們才是逃跑的角色呢
Dance, Wolffy!
跳舞吧，灰太狼
I forgot we don't have sky crystals anymore!
都忘記手上沒天晶了
Magic Train is garbage without sky crystal!
沒有天晶的嘻哈號就是一堆破爛
Get a taste of my Sirius missile!
讓你們嚐嚐我的天狼飛彈
I'll see how long you can dodge this!
我看你們能躲到什麼時候
Don't hurt the goats, Wolffy!
灰太狼，不許傷害小羊
You're also here, Cloud Giant?
沒想到雲巨人你也來了
Wolffy, you can't escape this time!
灰太狼，我看你這次往哪跑
I'll admit defeat, all right?
本大王認輸還不行嗎？
You can have sky crystal. Go look for it!
天晶給你們，去找吧！
Wolffy, you--
灰太狼，你…
I have sky crystal!
找到天晶了
It's a marble! Wolffy fooled us!
怎麼會是玻璃彈珠？ 我們被灰太狼給騙了！
Sky crystal is mine now!
現在天晶是我的了
Oh, no. We are too late.
糟了，我們來晚了
Perfect timing.
來得正好
Let me show you the true power of sky crystal!
我要讓你們看看 什麼是天晶真正的力量
TO BE CONTINUED
（未完待續）